Ismail Ahmadi

Full Stack Web Developer

Ismail7ahmadi@gmail.com | (+1) 365-476-2022 | Ismailahmadi.com | Linkedin.com/in/ismail-ahmadi | Github.com/Ismail-ahmadi

Profile Summary

Self-motivated and goal-oriented Web / Software Development professional with 2+ years of experience in building, developing, and maintaining functional and aesthetically responsive websites and web apps. Proficient at utilizing analytical and critical thinking skills for user-friendly interaction, efficiency, and consistency. Expertise in both frontend and back-end web development using technologies such as JavaScript, Python, Java, PHP, MySQL, Node JS, React JS, Linux, jQuery, HTML and CSS/SASS. Currenly enrolled in Full Stack .NET Colud Developer - a Briding Program at Humber College expanding more technical skills such as C#, Windows Desktop Applications, SQL Server, .NET Core, Miscrosoft's cloud Azure, Typscript, Web Secuity in OWASP, and Angular. Strong ability to build solid relationships with team members and collaborate effectively through excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages : JavaScript (ES6), Java, Python, PHP, SQL.

HTML, CSS/SASS, Template Engine (Liquid/Pug).

Libraries & Framework : Node JS, React JS, jQuery, DOM, Bootstrap, Express, Mongo DB - Mongosse.

Tools, Platforms, & ... : Git (GitHub), MySQL, Netlify, WordPress, Joomla, Linux, Hyper, Agile, MS. Office.

Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, and Adobe InDesign.

Relevant Work Experience

Junior Programmer @TADZ Venture PTE LTD (intern), Indonesia

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

- Successfully developed and validated a funding feature using JavaScript, jQuery, Python, JSON, HTML and CSS, resulting in functional, robust, object-oriented code with an aesthetically pleasing and user-friendly design.
- Implemented ERPNext configuration and customization on a cloud server for a fundraising platform.
- ➤ Collaborated with the technical team and actively participated in online meetings, and provided regular project updates using Asana.

Project Coordinator & Instructor @YICF (Yayasan Internasional Cahaya Fajar), Indonesia

Apr 2019 - Jul 2019

- ➤ Coordinated and created a successful vocational web development training program, covering HTML, CSS/SASS, GitHub, and JavaScript.
- ➤ Created and organized the syllabus and resources on Trello, and delivered lessons to classes of 15-18 students.
- ➤ Provided one-to-one sessions with students to ensure understanding and mastery of course material, resulting, 50% of the students finding jobs as data annotators directly due to skills learned in the course. Another 20% of the class continued on to the second section of the course in JavaScript.

Web Developer @Going Green in Jakarta Community, Indonesia

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

- ▶ Built, developed, and maintained a website using JavaScript, Git (GitHub), Netlify, Adobe Photoshop, Template Engine Liquid, CSS3 / SASS, HTML5 to disseminate environmentally friendly awareness to the Community.
- ➤ Designed and developed new features as required and regularly gathered, compiled, and created the website content through meetings with a small group of the community members.

- Assisted and monitored the designing class of 15 civil servants of DM-TVET (Deputy Ministry of Technical and Vocational Education and Training) in Adobe Photoshop and Adobe InDesign, restuled in development of participants' design skills and successful completion of the class.
- ➤ Taught various techniques and strategies for graphics and layout design. Resulted in 5 students being selected to work for the newly created design department for the Deputy Ministry's magazine.

Information Technology Assistant @CGSO -CANADEM, Afghanistan

Jan 2011 - Jul 2011

- ➤ Collaborated with and provided immediate IT support for high-ranking authorities in Ministry of Justice, ensuring the smooth operation of IT systems.
- Managed and oversaw an online database connected to a CMS (Joomla), and facilitated accessibility of over 50 laws, legislations, and regulations in English, Dari, and Pashtu, increasing accessibility and understanding of legal materials for a wider audience.

Web Designer @SabaHiTech (intern), Afghanistan

Jan 2010 - Dec 2010

- ▶ Designed various website layouts and landing pages in Adobe Photoshop, Incorporating client feedback to create visually appealing designs and achieve desired color and layout.
- Successfully developed and built static websites using HTML, CSS, and Adobe Dreamweaver for three clients, meeting project deadlines and exceeding client expectations.

Education & Certifications

Full Stack .NET Cloud Developer, @Humber College, ON, Canada	Jan 2023 – Jun 2023
Workplace Preparation Program, @Mohawk College, ON, Canada	Nov 2022 - Feb 2023
Associate Degreee in Computer Science, @University of the People, California, USA	Apr 2021 - Oct 2022
Complete Web Development Certificate (100H), @Udemy by Development Island (UK)	Jun 2021 - Oct 2022
Associate Degree of Arts of Honors, @Broward College, Florida, USA	Aug 2019 - Agu 2022

Volunterring

English Teacher & Teacher Assistant @Roshan Learning Center, Indonesia

Oct 2017 - Dec 2019

- ➤ Observed and provided support and assistance for a class of 18 students, substituted for the teacher when necessary, resulting in all students progressing to the next level.
- ➤ Taught English for general purposes to adult refugee students with minimal literacy in their native language and elementary knowledge of English.
- Created lesson plans, attained informal teachings training, implemented a variety of learning methods while teaching, managed class dynamics for classes of up to 16 students in different age categories, conducted evaluation for betterment and needs of the student, resulting in 70% of the students progressing to the next level by the end of the first year.

Languages

English Persian (Farsi/Dari) Indonesian